Guide to the Signal Archive ca. 1963-1965 MSS.024
Fales Library and Special Collections
Signal Archive
ca. 1963-1965
Fales Library and Special Collections
Signal
MSS.024
0.25 Linear Feet
The Signal Archive contains correspondence and manuscripts submitted to the journal's editor, Bret Rohmer. Signal was a literary journal focused primarily on poetry. Three issues were produced between 1963 and 1965. Many of the authors are notable figures in Beat poetry, the New York School, and the Black Mountain poets.
Historical Note
Signal: A Quarterly Review was a literary journal published by the Brownstone Press in New York focusing primarily on poetry. Three issues were produced between 1963 and 1965. Many of the authors are notable figures associated with Beat poetry, the New York School, and the Black Mountain poets. Signal's chief editor was Bret Rohmer and the co-editors were Diane Di Prima and Paul Z. Panish.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Arrangement
Corrsepondence from unidentified authors is arranged chronologically; all other correspondence and manuscripts are arranged by the author's last name.
Missing Title
Series I: Correspondence
Scope and Content note
The Signal Archive contains correspondence and manuscripts submitted to the journal's editor, Bret Rohmer. Notable authors of manuscript submissions include Hart Crane, Diane Di Prima, Kirby Doyle, LeRoi Jones, Ron Loewinsohn, David Meltzer, W.S. Merwin, Frank O'Hara, Joel Oppenheimer, Michael Rumaker, John Thomas, John Wieners, and Paul Zweig.
Poetry |y 20th century |v Periodicals.; Poetry, Modern -- 20th century.; American poetry -- 20th century -- Periodicals; Beat generation.; Black Mountain school (Group of poets); American literature -- 20th century.; American poetry -- 20th century.; Small presses -- New York (State) -- New York.; Downtown writers.; Wieners, John, 1934-2002; Waring, James; Oppenheimer, Joel; Crane, Hart, 1899-1932; Dawson, Fielding, 1930-2002; Rohmer, Bret, 1934-; Di Prima, Diane; Zweig, Paul; Thomas, John, 1930-2002; Doyle, Kirby; Loewinsohn, Ron; Meltzer, David; Baraka, Amiri, 1934-2014; Merwin, W. S. (William Stanley), 1927-2019; O'Hara, Frank, 1926-1966; Rumaker, Michael, 1932-
- Correspondence
  Scope and Content
  This series contains correspondence and manuscripts submitted to Bret Rohmer.
  - Correspondence from: Unidentified., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript: Ashley, L.R.N., undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript: Basara, Bob., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript: Crane, Hart., undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript: Dawson, Fielding., undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript: Di Prima, Diane., undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Manuscript: Doyle, Kirby., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Manuscript: Insect Trust., undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Manuscript: Irwin, Jed., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Manuscript: Jonas, Steve., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Manuscript: Jones, LeRoi., undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Manuscript: Kleinbard, David J., undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Manuscript: Lansing, Gerrit., undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Manuscript: Levy, William J., undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Manuscript: Lima, Frank., undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Manuscript: Loewinsohn, Ron., undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Manuscript: Matson, Clive., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Manuscript: Meltzer, David., undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Manuscript: Merwin, W.S., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Manuscript: O'Hara, Frank., undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Manuscript: Oppenheimer, Joel., undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Manuscript: Parish, Paul Z., undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Manuscript: Passage, Charles., undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Manuscript: Rohmer, Bret., undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Manuscript: Rumaker, Michael., undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Manuscript: Thomas, John., undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Manuscript: Waring, James., undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Manuscript: Wieners, John., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Manuscript: Zuk, Raymond Williams., undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Manuscript: Zweig, Paul., undated (Box 1, Folder 30)